# Wissem Karous

🗷 karouswissem@gmail.com 🔲 +21695091425 🛅 in/wissem-karous 📤 https://wissemkarous.github.io

## **ABOUT ME**

I am currently a student in telecommunications engineering. I have a strong passion for data science and artificial intelligence, with experience in manipulating, training, and fine-tuning machine learning models. I am also passionate about open-source software.

# **EDUCATION**

# Telecommunications Engineering Student September 2022, Present Sfax

• National School of Electronics and Telecommunications of Sfax.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Computer Science Intern**

Business Software July 2023 - August 2023, Sfax

- Crafted a mobile app for attendance tracking to achieve accurate results and resolve the issue where 5% of employees work in remote environments.
- ++ Used Tech Stack: React Native, TensorFlow.js, Express.js, MongoDB.

## **Data Science Intern**

CodeClause

March 2023 - April 2023, Online

- ullet Implemented an approach to classify emails as spam or not spam with 100% accuracy.
- · Used the BeautifulSoup library to perform web scraping and extracted data on ISIMS teachers into a CSV file containing 100 entries.
- Developed a system that uses a facial emotion detection approach to extract emotions from a webcam with an accuracy rate of 97%.

# **PROJECTS**

- · End-Of-Year Project:
- + Built a model with a web interface based on Streamlit for lipreading tasks, achieving the lowest CER (0.6%) and WER (1.7%) since the first paper was published in 2016.
- + Analyzed 8 research papers leading to the extraction of key elements in the project.
- Sentiment Analysis based NLP with 2 labels .
- Designed an anxiety test with the Streamlit platform featuring 4 types of questions.
- Predictive marketing modeling based on K-means and PCA (centers the most significant variance in 1/3 of its principal components).

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **Vector Databases**

DeepLearning.Ai • 2024

• Vector Databases: From Embeddings to Applications.

# **Machine Learning with python**

IBM • 2023

· Machine Learning models.

# **SKILLS**

AI libraries: Scikit-learn, transformers, TensorFlow, Keras.OpenCv

Version control: Git, GitHub, huggingface

Frameworks: Gradio, Streamlit

Programming languages: python, java, C, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Machine Learning fields: AI, NLP, DL, LLMs

# **COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT**

#### Instructor

Google Developer Student Clubs (Machine Learning Department Lead)

September 2023 - April 2024, Sfax

- $\bullet \ \ Delivered \ Machine \ Learning \ workshops \ to \ more \ than \ 25 \ students \ across \ 10 \ sessions.$
- · Composed comprehensive learning guidelines by creating a GitHub repository and reviewing assignments with GitHub Classroom.